<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>https://mbuze.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://mbuze.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Curriculum Vitae</title>
      <link>https://mbuze.github.io/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mbuze.github.io/cv/</guid>
      <description>Career and Education  2023 - Present  Research Associate at School of Mathematical and Computer Sciences, Heriot-Watt University, Edinburgh, UK; working on several EPSRC-funded projects about mathematical theory of polycrystalline materials with Prof. John Ball, Dr David Bourne, Dr Lucia Scardia.   2022 - 2023  Research Fellow at School of Mathematics, University of Birmingham, UK; working on an EPSRC-funded project about analysis of evolutionary PDEs as gradient flows arising from Optimal Transportation Theory with Dr Hong Duong;  organising the Reading Group on Mathematics of Data Science (see Events).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Events</title>
      <link>https://mbuze.github.io/events/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mbuze.github.io/events/</guid>
      <description>Maxwell Analysis Day; ICMS, Edinburgh, UK, 27 March 2024; A half-day event bringing together the HW and UoE analysis groups; organiser on behalf of HW.    Workshop on Optimal Transport, Humboldt University of Berlin; Berlin, Germany, 11 - 15 March 2024; poster presentation; website.    Centre for Mathematical Imaging Techniques Seminar, University of Liverpool; Liverpool, UK, 28 February 2024; seminar talk.    Analysis Seminar, University of Strathclyde; Glasgow, 5 December 2023.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://mbuze.github.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mbuze.github.io/publications/</guid>
      <description>[9]   M.&amp;nbsp;Buze. Constrained Hellinger-Kantorovich barycenters: least-cost soft and conic multi-marginal formulations. arXiv e-prints, 2402.11268, 2024. [&amp;nbsp;bib&amp;nbsp;| http&amp;nbsp;| .pdf&amp;nbsp;]   [8]   PyAPD: A Python library for computing anisotropic power diagrams using GPU acceleration, 2023. [&amp;nbsp;bib&amp;nbsp;| http&amp;nbsp;]   [7]   M.&amp;nbsp;Buze and M.H. Duong. Entropic regularisation of unbalanced optimal transportation problems. arXiv e-prints, 2305.02410, 2023. [&amp;nbsp;bib&amp;nbsp;| http&amp;nbsp;| .pdf&amp;nbsp;]   [6]   M.&amp;nbsp;Buze, T.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://mbuze.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mbuze.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>Collaborators:   Université Bourgogne Franche-Comté, France: Geneviève Dusson.    University of Birmingham, UK Hong Duong (former postdoctoral mentor)    Cardiff University, UK: Angela Mihai (former postdoctoral mentor), Thomas Woolley    University of Glasgow, UK: Steven Roper    Heriot-Watt University, UK: John Ball (postdoctoral mentor), David Bourne (postdoctoral mentor), Julian Braun, Lucia Scardia (postdoctoral mentor)    University of British Columbia, Canada: Christoph Ortner (PhD advisor).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>https://mbuze.github.io/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mbuze.github.io/teaching/</guid>
      <description>Teaching at Heriot-Watt 2023/2024   Lecturer for F17XB Mathematics for Engineers and Scientists 2; A big service course for 500+ students across three campuses.    Guest Lecturer for F17CB Calculus B;     Teaching at Warwick  2018/2019   Supervisions of second-year Maths students, Term 1; modules covered: MA244 Analysis III, MA251 Algebra I: Advanced Linear Algebra, MA259 Multivariable Calculus.   2017/2018  Supervisions of first-year Maths&amp;Physics students, Terms 1 &amp; 2; same modules as in previous year&#39;s supervisions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
